Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Physics, Photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Physics, photographs
1910-1973
1950-1973
PC0131
Stanford University. Department of Physics.
8.5 Linear feet
Collection contains photographs of faculty, staff, and students, 1910-1973, with the bulk of the images from 1965-1973. Most of the photos appear to be identification images, some of which show signs of having been posted on display. There are also images of Prof. William Webster Hansen; the farewell party for Ed. A. Wright (mechanician) in 1942; Prof. Fernando Sanford with a group on the steps of a house ca. 1910; and undated portraits of 19th century German physicists: Max Planck, Gustav Kirchhoff, Hermann von Helmholtz, and two others.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Collection contains photographs of faculty, staff, and students, 1910-1973, with the bulk of the images from 1965-1973. Most of the photos appear to be identification images, some of which show signs of having been posted on display. There are also images of Prof. William Webster Hansen; the farewell party for Ed. A. Wright (mechanician) in 1942; Prof. Fernando Sanford with a group on the steps of a house ca. 1910; and undated portraits of 19th century German physicists: Max Planck, Gustav Kirchhoff, Hermann von Helmholtz, and two others.
Access Terms
Hansen, W. W. (William Webster), 1909-1949; Helmholtz, Hermann von, 1821-1894.; Kirchhoff, G. (Gustav), 1824-1887.; Planck, Max, 1858-1947.; Sanford, Fernando.; Stanford University. Department of Physics. Faculty.; Stanford University. Department of Physics.; Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- Photographs
  - Rolled 35mm negatives (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rolled 35mm negatives (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rolled 35mm negatives (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Portrait negatives A 1971: J. Anderson; R. Avida (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Portrait negatives B 1971: K. Baker; U. Bar-Gadda; K. Bethel; D. Boyd; R. Boyd (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Portrait negatives C 1971: C. Campbell; C. Cho; A. Chiu (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Portrait negatives D 1971: D. Dahl; B. DeWitt; E. Diener; N. Dixon; G. Donaldson; B. Donnelly; Dubach (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Portrait negatives F-H 1971: S. Fiarman; Z. Guiragossian; D. Haskin; Haxton (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Portrait negatives I-K 1971: M. Ibarra; M. Iverson; B. Keister; G. King; G. Kumbartzki (?); M. Kronick (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Portrait negatives L-M 1971: La Pointe; J. Laluda (?); Ch. Lee; M. Lin; M. Masujima; D. Mavis; E. Motiska (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Portrait negatives O-P 1971: H. Orbach; R. Peccei; R. Pearson; M. Peterson (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Portrait negatives R 1971: R. Rand; R. Reitz; O. Roberts; R. Running (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Portrait negatives S 1971: R. Schilling; T. Sharpton; D. Slater; S. Spence (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Portrait negatives T-W 1971: M. Turner; R. Walton; R. Wedmeyer; S. West; T. Winkler (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Portrait negatives, unidentified (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Portraits (contact sheets, with a few name identifications), 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Portraits (proofs), 1966/67 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Portraits (contact sheets, with a few name identifications), 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Portraits (contact sheets), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Physics picnic, B/W snapshots, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: A-B (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: C-D (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: E - F (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: G-H (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: I-K (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: L-M (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: N-O (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: P (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: Q-R (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: S (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: T-V (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: W-Z (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: unidentified women (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: unidentified men (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of faculty, staff, students: unidentified men (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Portrait negatives undated A-B: Alton, Bell, Bernstein, Blandenbecker (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Portrait negatives undated C-F: Cotts, Dahlberg, Downs, Drummond, Duffy, de Flarys, Franken, Fried (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Portrait negatives undated H-K: Harless, Helm, Hobart, Hofstadter, Jaynes, Kirkpatrick, Kliger, Kraushoar (?) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Portrait negatives undated L-P: Lamb, Maiman, Meyerhoff, Pake, Poirier (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Portrait negatives undated S: Schiff, Smith, Stogryn, Strickland, Sundfors (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Portrait negatives undated T-Y: Taylor, Wieder, Wilcox, Yearian, Yenvie (?), Yodh (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Passport negatives 1972 or 1973: Ammons, Beron, Bloom, Boughn, Brill, Ceperley, Colson, Cubeddo (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Passport negatives 1972 or 1973: Day, Donnelly, Duryee, H. Fairbank, W. Fairbank, Fetter, Fields, Fisher, Flexer (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Passport negatives 1972 or 1973: Gerber, Gilchriese, Hall, Hallak, Hansch, Hawkines, Heile, Hitlin (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Passport negatives 1972 or 1973: Kampas, Kennelly, Koch, Kuhlmann, LaRue, Lazarus, Le Coultre, Li (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Passport negatives 1972 or 1973: Meyerhof, Rand, Saylor, Triplett, Turneaure, Wikswo, Yuen (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Notebook of 35mm negatives, undated, unidentified (includes some Stanford sports photos, dogs, people, museum displays, travel images; at least one negative matches a print that was labeled “from William Hansen personnel file”) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Photographs identified as “from William Hansen personnel file” (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Photographs from Physics events or groups 1942 and undated: includes images of Prof. Kirkpatrick, the farewell party for Ed. A. Wright mechanician in 1942, and Prof. Fernando Sanford with a group on the steps of a house ca. 1910 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Portraits, older: J. G. Brown, Bruce Bush, Albert Pruden Carman, G. R. Harrison (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Portraits, older: D. W. Murphy, F. J. Rogers, Fernando Sanford, Herman De Clercq Stearns (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Portraits, older: M. E. Taylor, D. L. Webster (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Portraits of 19th century German physicists: Max Planck, Gustav Kirchhoff, Hermann von Helmholtz, and 2 others (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Physics building, photograph of architectural sketch (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Photographs from a fishing trip [no identification of people], ca. 1910 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Photograph from a group meeting [labeled on back: “1906. The American Society for the Advancement of Polygamy, Stanford University Chapter” and in pencil: “also known as the Lorentz Symposium, University of Wisconsin, about 1921” CAUTION: item was unframed but the photo is still adhered to the glass on lower left corner.] (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - List of people in “Physics Dept. Group 1914” [appears not to match any image in this collection] (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - One photograph, oversize, of Ron Wilensky, George Ryder, and Don Roc (?), labeled: “Neutrinos University Champions Pocket Billiards 1966-67” (Box 4)
- Glass Slides
  - 3.5 x 4 inch glass lantern slides, circa 1950s (Box 1-4)